Guide to the Bill Communications Sales and Marketing Management Vertical Files, 1960-1994
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Bill Communications Sales and Marketing Management Vertical Files 1960-1994
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Bill Communications, Inc.
11 linear feet Extent: 7,700 Items
Bill Communications, Inc., a subsidiary of Dutch publisher VNU Business Publications, is a business-to-business publisher and organizer of trade shows. Sales and Marketing Management is one of their main trade journals. The Bill Communications Sales and Marketing Management Vertical Files cover the years 1960-1994, with the bulk of the material dating 1975-1985. Topics include advertising, black middle class, finance, food industry, hiring, legal perspectives, management, marketing, media, packaging, product trends, real estate market, research, the Robinson-Patman Act, salesmen and salesmanship, research, telephone industry, training, women consumers, youth market and youth alcohol use, and zip codes. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
RL.00111
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Bill Communications Sales and Marketing Management Vertical Files were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1994.
Collection Overview
The Bill Communications Sales and Marketing Management Vertical Files cover the years 1960-1994, with the bulk of the material dating 1975-1985. Topics include advertising, black middle class, finance, food industry, hiring, legal perspectives, management, marketing, media, packaging, product trends, real estate market, research, the Robinson-Patman Act, salesmen and salesmanship, research, telephone industry, training, women consumers, youth market and youth alcohol use, and zip codes.
Collection Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by topic. Original folder titles were retained.
Subject Headings
Bill Communications, Inc.; VNU Business Publications (Firm); Sales and Marketing Management; Advertising -- United States; African American consumers; Food industry and trade -- United States; Marketing research -- United States; Real estate business -- United States; Sales executives -- United States; Sales force management -- United States; Sales forecasting -- United States; Sales management; Sales management -- United States; Sales meetings -- United States; Sales personnel -- United States; United States. Robinson-Patman Act; Women consumers -- United States; Young consumers -- United States; Youth -- Alcohol use; Zip codes -- United States; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Bates Worldwide, Inc. Records
J. Walter Thompson Company. Advertising and Marketing Intelligence Database Records
J. Walter Thompson Company. Albert B. Stridsberg Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Marketing Vertical Files
James O'Shaughnessy Papers
McGraw-Hill Marketing Information Center Vertical File
Popsicle Advertising Campaign Collection
Contents of Collection
- Bill Communications Vertical Files, 1960-1994, (18 boxes)
  - 10 Big Mistakes, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Advertising, 1972-1985, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Black middle class, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Black markets, 1985 (Box 1)
  - CA-TV, 1967-1982, (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Closing sales, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Compensations, 1977-1981 (Box 1)
  - Consumer research, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Cooperative advertising, 1976-1981 (Box 1)
  - Coupons, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Crystal, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Customer complaints, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Customer service, 1977-1980 (Box 1)
  - Direct marketing, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Drugstore packages, undated (Box 1)
  - Editorial philosophies and practices, 1961 (Box 1)
  - First line sales managers, 1969-1973 (Box 1)
  - Food, 1984-1986, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Food store packages, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Glace at markets, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Hatch a speech, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Hiring, 1972-1985, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Lafayette Hotel, undated (Box 2)
  - Letters to publisher, 1987-1988, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Managing the salesman's wife, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Man power games, 1970-1975 (Box 2)
  - Market analysis, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - Market research, 1978-1981 (Box 2)
  - Marketing, 1983-1985, (3 folders) (Box 2)
  - Media, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Meetings, 1872-1980 (Box 2)
  - Ms. Is a Hit, undated (Box 2)
  - Multinational marketing, undated (Box 2)
  - On the road, 1975-1981 (Box 2)
  - Physical distribution, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
  - Plateau salesmen, 1988 (Box 2)
    [Contains survey.]
  - Postal service, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Product training, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Public relations, 1972-1977 (Box 3)
  - Psychology, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Radio, 1980-1981 (Box 3)
  - Rail roads, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - Real estate, 1977, undated, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Recording industry, 1979-1983 (Box 3)
  - Records relations, 1981 and undated (Box 3)
  - Recruiters, 1978-1981 (Box 3)
  - References, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Research, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - restaurants, 1979-1982 (Box 3)
  - Robinson-Patman Act, 1960-1964 (Box 3)
    [Contains book on the Robinson-Patman Act and allowances within company.]
  - Retailing, 1975-1982, (3 folders) (Box 4)
  - Retirement plans, 1964-1985, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Sales budgeting, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Sales career, 1962-1982, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Sales control, 1976-1983, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Sales costs, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Sales forecasting, 1970-1976, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Sales force management, 1978-1981 (Box 5)
  - Sales incentive, 1975-1989, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Sales leads, 1977-1983, (1 of 2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Sales leads, 1977-1983 (continued), (2 of 2 folders) (Box 6)
  - Sales letters, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Sales Management, 1960-1983, (5 folders) (Box 6)
  - Sales Managers, 1968-1973 (Box 6)
  - Sales and Market Management (S&MM), 1980-1982, (1-2 of 3 folders) (Box 6)
  - S&MM, 1968-1973 (continued), (3 of 3 folders) (Box 7)
  - Sales meetings, 1972-1979, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Sales planing, 1875 (Box 7)
  - Sales promotion, 1980-1983 (Box 7)
  - Sales strategies, 1979-1981 (Box 7)
  - Sales training, 1973-1980, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Sales territories, 1977, undated, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Salesmen, 1964-1981, undated, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Salesmen attitude, undated (Box 8)
  - Salesmen call, 1961-1977 (Box 8)
  - Salesmen compensation, 1962-1978, (3 folders) (Box 8)
  - Salesmen expense allowance, 1970-1978 (Box 8)
  - Salesmen hiring, 1970-1982, (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - Salesmen industrial, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Salesmen job, 1959 (Box 8)
  - Salesmen performance, 1963-1977 (Box 8)
  - Salesmen specialization, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Salesmen time management, 1971-1977 (Box 9)
  - Salesmen turnover, 1973-1975 (Box 9)
  - Salesmen unionizing, 1963 (Box 9)
  - Salesmen wives, undated (Box 9)
  - Salesmen women, 1973-1978 (Box 9)
  - Salesmanship, 1966-1975, (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Security, 1980 (Box 9)
  - Seminars, 1981-1982, (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Service, 1972-1980 (Box 9)
  - Service industries, 1965-1974 (Box 9)
  - Service management, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Service marketing, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Shopping centers, 1960-1983, (1 of 3 folders) (Box 9)
  - Shopping centers, 1960-1983 (continued), (1-2 of 3 folders) (Box 10)
  - Ski resort, undated (Box 10)
  - Small business, 1976-1985, (2 folders) (Box 10)
  - Social security, 1977-1994, (3 folders) (Box 10)
    [Contains manuals; Annotated Readings in Social Security, and Social Security Programs Throughout the World 1981.]
  - Solar energy, 1974-1982, (1 of 2 folders) (Box 10)
  - Solar energy, 1974-1982 (continued), (2 of 2 folders) (Box 11)
  - Speakers, 1976-1994, (3 folders) (Box 11)
    [Contains book Speakers Directory 1976.]
  - Sports, 1979-1981 (Box 11)
  - Standards, 1976 (Box 11)
  - Standard industrial classification, 1968-1980 (Box 11)
  - Statistics, 1976-1980, (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - Steel, 1970-1977 (Box 11)
  - Strawberry speech, 1974 (Box 11)
  - Stress information, 1978-1979 (Box 11)
  - Stocks, 1992 (Box 12)
    [File contains magazine; Wall Street 20th Century.]
  - Super markets, 1979-1982, (3 folders) (Box 12)
    [File contains super market newspapers and magazines, and books; The National Study of Super Market Shoppers 1979-1980, and SN Distribution Study of Grocery Store Sales 1982.]
  - Survey-buying power, 1977-1978 (Box 12)
  - Survey-circulation, 1988, (3 folders) (Box 12)
    [Contains actual surveys filled out and blank survey forms.]
  - Survey-S&MM, 1979, (2 folders) (Box 13)
  - Suburbanization of retail, 1970 (Box 13)
  - T&E trends, 1988 (Box 13)
  - Taxes, 1972-1986, (4 folders) (Box 13)
  - Telecommunications, 1983-1990 (Box 13)
  - Telephone industry, 1972, (1 of 2 folders) (Box 13)
  - Telephone industry, 1972 (continued), (2 of 2 folders) (Box 14)
  - Telephone selling, 1977-1981, (2 folders) (Box 14)
  - Telemarketing, 1983-1984 (Box 14)
  - Television, 1973-1982, (5 folders) (Box 14)
    [File contains TV guides, and rating guides.]
  - Textiles, 1967 (Box 14)
  - Tobacco, 1960-1980 (Box 14)
  - Tough customer, 1978-1979 (Box 15)
  - Toy trends, 1980 (Box 15)
  - Trademarks, 1960-1983 (Box 15)
  - Trade shows, 1967-1980 (Box 15)
  - Trading stamps, 1960-1964 (Box 15)
    [Contains booklets on how to trade stamps and the economic value of stamp trading.]
  - Transportation, 1975-1987, (2 folders) (Box 15)
  - Travel, 1975-1982, (1-2 of 6 folders) (Box 15)
    [Contains book Travel Trends in the United States and Canada and copies of travel magazines.]
  - Travel, 1975-1982 (continued), (3-6 of 6 folders) (Box 16)
    [Contains newsletters on tourism and travel. Also includes books; Bibliography on tourism and Travel-Research Studies, Reports and Articles Vol I-III.]
  - Trends, 1984-1985 (Box 16)
  - Universal product code, 1973-1976, (2 folders) (Box 17)
    [Contains book; Directory of UGPCC Members of the Fall/Winter 1974.]
  - Utilities, 1983 (Box 17)
  - Video industry, 1979-1982 (Box 17)
  - Water, 1966-1983 (Box 17)
  - Warranties, 1972-1975 (Box 17)
  - Wholesale, 1964-1977 (Box 17)
  - Women, 1970-1978, (3 folders) (Box 17)
  - Wood, 1980 (Box 18)
  - Word processing, 1960 (Box 18)
  - Youth market, 1974-1993, (4 folders) (Box 18)
    [Contains book Young Adults: Distilled Spirits Study 1975, and studies on the college market.]
  - Zip codes, 1978-1981, (2 folders) (Box 18)